(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-12T16:46:23.592024",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ぺこら ありがとう Live Birthday 2022
[Pekora "Arigatou" Live Birthday 2022]
ぺこーら ありがとう Live
Pekora “Arigatou” Live
桜が咲くよ 見慣れたいつもの坂道に
The cherry blossoms bloom on this familiar hill path,
ああ 別れを 泣いて笑ったあの日々は
Ah, parting... those days of crying and laughing
なんだか昨日のことのよう
feel almost like yesterday.
この道はそう 未来へ続く道
This path is, yes, a path leading to the future...
さよならメモリーズ
Sayonara Memories
泣いて笑った あの日々は
Those days of crying and laughing
なんだか昨日のことのよう
feel almost like yesterday.
この道はそう 未来へ続く道
This path is, yes, a path leading to the future...
さよならメモリーズ
Sayonara Memories
例年より早い 開花予報を
The earlier-than-usual cherry blossom forecast
キミは嬉しがってた
you were so happy about.
私は笑って「そうだね」と言った
I just smiled and said, "That's right."
あと少ししたらもう ここには戻れないのに
Even though in just a little while we won't be able to return here,
言葉じゃうまく言えない想いを キミに打ち明けられたならって
wondering if I could confide in you these feelings I can't put into words...
伝えよう 最初で最後
I'll convey them, for the first and last time.
いつか一緒に帰った道は 私にとって特別な思い出
The road we once walked home together is a special memory to me.
忘れないよ さよならメモリーズ
I won't forget it. Sayonara Memories.
春が来たら それぞれの道を
When spring comes, we'll take our separate paths,
また会える日を願って 小さくつぶやいた
whispering softly, hoping for the day we can meet again.
空はあの日と変わらず 青くてだからちょっと泣けた
The sky is just as blue as that day, which made me cry a little.
わざと遠回りしたの 少しでも長くキミの隣にいたくて
I took a detour on purpose, wanting to stay by your side just a little longer.
私はおどけて「まちがえた！」と言った
I playfully said, "Oops, I took a wrong turn!"
キミは笑う その顔が まぶしくて目をそらした
You laughed, and that dazzling smile made me look away.
言葉じゃうまく言えない想いを 胸に抱いてこの道を歩いた
Carrying feelings I couldn't put into words in my heart, I walked down this road.
覚えてる あの時キミは 私の名前を呼んでくれた
I remember, back then you called out my name.
二人 夕暮れの帰り道で
The two of us on the way home at dusk...
忘れないよ さよならメモリーズ
I won't forget it. Sayonara Memories.
出逢えた事 感謝してる 初めてみた満開の桜
I'm grateful we met—the full-bloom cherry blossoms I saw for the very first time.
あれからどれくらい 変われたんだろう 一見見た時に思ったんだ
How much have I changed since then? I wondered the moment I first saw you,
この人の事 好きになりそうって
thinking, "I think I'm going to fall in love with this person."
なんでかな わからないよ
I wonder why? I really don't know.
それからの毎日はとても楽しくて でも同じくらいに辛かったんだ
Every day after that was so much fun, yet at the same time, just as painful.
ごめんね なんかうまく言えないよ
Sorry, I can't quite say it right.
だから 私 キミと なんて言うか 今のまま さよならしたくないよ 友達のまま じゃ もう嫌なの
That's why... I... with you... how should I put it? I don't want to say goodbye just like this, staying as just friends, I hate that anymore!
言おうと思ってた 私 キミの キミのこと ずっと ずっと 前から 好きでした
I was going to say... I've loved you... you... always, always, ever since a long time ago!
ああ やっと言えた
Ah, I finally said it.
春が来たら それぞれの道を
When spring comes, we'll take our separate paths,
また会える日を願って 小さくつぶやいた
whispering softly, hoping for the day we can meet again.
空はあの日と変わらず 青くてだからちょっと泣けた
The sky is just as blue as that day, which made me cry a little.
はじめて見た 満開の桜
The full-bloom cherry blossoms I saw for the very first time...
あれからどれくらい 変われたんだろう
How much have I changed since then?
変われたんだろ
Have I really changed?
春が来たら それぞれの道を
When spring comes, we'll take our separate paths...
桜が咲くよ 見慣れたいつもの坂道に ああ 別れを
Cherry blossoms bloom on the familiar slope we always walked down... Ah, parting ways.
泣いて笑ったあの日々は何だか昨日のことのよう
Those days of crying and laughing feel almost like yesterday.
わかんないよ
I don't understand.
それからの毎日はとても楽しくって
Ever since then, every day has been so fun,
だけど同じくらいにつらかったんだ
but also just as painful.
つながんだ ああ...
Linked together... Ah...
ごめんね なんかうまく言えないよ だから私キミとなんて言うか
Sorry, I can't express it well. That's why I... how should I say it to you...
今のままじゃ さよならしたくないの
I don't want to say goodbye just like this.
友達のままでじゃ もう嫌なの
I hate remaining just friends anymore!
言おうと思ってた 私キミの キミのことずっとずっと前から好きでした ああ やっと言えた
I was planning to tell you... I've loved you, yes you, for a long, long time... Ah, I finally said it.
私 キミの キミのこと ずっと前から
I've... loved you, you, for a long time...
ああ...
Ah...
やっと言えた ああ...
I finally said it, ah...
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ペコちゃん、やめへんで！
Wait a minute! Peko-chan, don't stop yet!
兎田一番！
Usada Number One!
キミにも見える 兎田の星
The star of Usada that you can see too,
ゆけゆけ兎田 おのれのために
Go, go, Usada, for your own sake!
夢はでかいぜ 世界制服
Our dreams are huge: conquer the world!
めざせ兎田 おのれのために
Aim high, Usada, for your own sake!
兎田一番！
Usada Number One!
キミにも見える 兎田の星
The star of Usada that you can see too,
ゆけゆけ兎田 おのれのために
Go, go, Usada, for your own sake!
夢はでかいぜ 世界征服 めざせ兎田 おのれのために
Our dreams are huge: conquer the world! Aim high, Usada, for your own sake!
兎田一番！
Usada Number One!
あの日の誓い ヤクソクの地へ 進め兎田 おのれのために
To the land of the oath we made that day, advance, Usada, for your own sake!
兎田一番！
Usada Number One!
たとえ嵐が 吹き荒れるとも めざせ兎田 おのれのために
Even if a storm rages on, aim high, Usada, for your own sake!
兎田一番！
Usada Number One!
Usada's number one!
走れ走れ！
Run, run!
歩け歩け！
Walk, walk!
よっしゃ！
Alright!
21世紀はおまかせ
Leave the 21st century to us!
誰が2番ですか！？
Who's number two!?
俺を見ろ！
Look at me!
ワオ！
Wow!
ヤッター！
Yay!
バイナラー
Bye-bye!
兎田 一番！
Usada's number one!
Are you ready?
yeah!
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey
あいつもこいつもあの席を ただ一つ狙っているんだよ
Everyone's after that one seat
このクラスで一番の 美人の隣を
Next to the hottest girl in this class
ああ みんなライバルさ ああ いのちがけだよ
Ah, everyone's a rival, ah, it's life or death
Yeah, yeah, yeah
運命の女神様よ このぼくにあほほえんで
Oh, goddess of fate, smile down on me
一度だけでも 勉強する気もしない気もこのときにかかっているんだよ
Just once... It all hinges on this moment
もし駄目ならこのぼくは もうグレちまうよ
If it doesn't work out, I'll just go off the rails
二枚目気取りの秀才も あのいやな悪党番長も
The wannabe heartthrob and annoying bully are both
胸はずませ待っている どの席になるか
Waiting with bated breath to see where they'll sit
ああ あの横顔を ああ 見つめられたら
Ah, if I catch a glimpse of that profile
Yeah, yeah, yeah
授業中 天国だよ このぼくにしあわせを与えておくれ
Class is like heaven, bring me some happiness
勉強する気もしない気もこのときにかかっているんだよ
I don't even feel like studying, it all hinges on this moment
もし駄目ならこのぼくは もうグレちまうよ
If it doesn't work out, I'll just go off the rails
世界は恋に落ちている 光の矢胸をさす
The whole world is falling in love, an arrow of light shoots through my heart
君をわかりたいんだよ 「ねえ、教えて」
I want to understand you. "Hey, tell me"
世界は恋に落ちている 光の矢胸をさす
The whole world is falling in love, an arrow of light shoots through my heart
君をわかりたいんだよ 「ねえ、教えて」
I want to understand you, "Hey, tell me"
すれ違う言葉にちょっとだけの後悔 涙こぼれて
When our words miss each other, just tears of regret flow
忙しい感情 鼓動にリンクする チューニング確かめたいんだ
Busy feelings link together in our heart, I want to make sure it's tuned correctly
すれ違う言葉にちょっとだけの後悔
When our words miss each other, just a bit of regret
涙こぼれて 忙しい感情 鼓動にリンクする
Tears spill over, busy feelings linking with our heartbeats
目的ばかりにとらわれて 大切なものが霞んで逃げて
I'm entirely taken by my motives, losing sight of what's important
今日もリスタート 世界は恋に落ちている 光の矢胸をさす
And restart again. The whole world is falling in love, an arrow of light shoots through my heart
世界は恋に落ちている
The world is falling in love,
光の矢胸を射す
an arrow of light piercing my heart.
全部わかりたいんだよ
I want to understand everything.
「ねえ、教えて」
"Hey, tell me."
すれ違う言葉に ちょっとだけの後悔
Just a little regret in our crossed words,
涙こぼれて
tears overflowing.
忙しい感情 鼓動にリンクする
Busy feelings link with my heartbeat,
チューニング確かめたいんだ
I want to check my tuning.
目的ばっかりにとらわれて
Caught up only in our goals,
大事なものが煙って逃げて
what's important gets hazy and escapes.
今日もリスタート
Today is a restart once again.
世界は恋に落ちている
The world is falling in love,
光の矢胸を射す
an arrow of light piercing my heart.
全部わかりたいんだよ
I want to understand everything.
「ねえ、聞かせて」
"Hey, let me hear it."
たった1ミリが遠くて
Just one millimeter away,
駆け抜けた日々に
in the days we ran through—
忘れない 忘れられない
Unforgettable, irreplaceable,
輝く1ページ
a shining page.
お似合いの二人になんだか複雑な
For a well-suited pair, somehow
気持ちがあるよ
I have complicated feelings.
初めての感情 鼓動にリンクする
My first-ever feelings link with my heartbeat.
体温計壊れちゃったかな?
Wonder if my thermometer broke?
自分のこと分からないまま
Without even understanding myself,
あの子にアドバイスまでしちゃって
I even gave that girl advice,
胸が痛いよ...
and now my chest hurts...
世界は恋に落ちている
The world is falling in love,
光の矢胸を射す
an arrow of light piercing my heart.
気付いたこの想いは
This feeling I realized—
「もう、遅いんだ」
"It's already too late."
あの子の方が可愛いって知ってるんだけど
I know that girl is cuter than me, but...
君のこと全部わかりたいって思っちゃう
I find myself wanting to understand everything about you.
これが恋だって初めて気付いたの
I realized for the first time that this is love.
絶対振り向いてほしい
I definitely want you to turn around and look at me.
遠かったけど諦めたくない
Even though it was so far, I don't want to give up.
好きだから
Because I love you.
春に咲いた花が恋をした
A flower that bloomed in spring fell in love,
花は必死に上を向いて笑った
and the flower desperately looked up and smiled.
青い夏の蕾も恋をした
A bud in the blue summer also fell in love,
咲かない花と火薬の匂い
an unblooming flower and the scent of gunpowder.
本当の気持ち言葉にして
Putting my true feelings into words,
大事なこと話せたら
if I can talk about what's important—
今日もリスタート
Today is a restart once again.
肝心な君だから
Because you're the crucial one,
口に出して言わなきゃ
I have to say it out loud.
今君に伝えるよ
I'll tell you right now—
「ねえ、好きです」
"Hey, I love you."
世界は恋に落ちている
The world is falling in love,
光の矢胸を射す
an arrow of light piercing my heart.
全部わかりたいんだよ
I want to understand everything.
「ねえ、聞かせて」
"Hey, let me hear it."
タグり寄せて もう0センチ
Reeling you in to zero centimeters.
駆け抜けた日々に
In the days we ran through—
忘れない 忘れられない 輝く1ページ
unforgettable, irreplaceable, a shining page.
青い夏の蕾も恋をした
A bud in the blue summer also fell in love,
咲かない花と火薬の匂い
an unblooming flower and the scent of gunpowder.
本当の気持ち言葉にして
Putting my true feelings into words,
大事なこと話せたら
if I can talk about what's important—
今日もリスタート
Today is a restart once again.
鈍感な君だから
Because you're dense,
口に出して言わなきゃ
I have to say it out loud.
今君に伝えるよ
I'll tell you right now—
「ねえ、好きです」
"Hey, I love you."
世界は恋に落ちている
The world is falling in love,
光の矢胸を射す
an arrow of light piercing my heart.
全部わかりたいんだよ
I want to understand everything.
「ねえ、聞かせて」
"Hey, let me hear it."
タグり寄せて もう0センチ
Reeling you in to zero centimeters.
駆け抜けた日々に
In the days we ran through—
忘れない 忘れられない 輝く1ページ
unforgettable, irreplaceable, a shining page.
すれ違う言葉に
Just a little regret in our crossed words,
ちょっとだけの後悔
tears overflowing.
涙こぼれて
Busy feelings link with my heartbeat,
忙しい感情 鼓動にリンクする
I want to check my tuning.
チューニング確かめたいんだ
Caught up only in our goals,
目的ばっかりにとらわれて
what's important gets hazy and escapes.
大事なものが煙って逃げて
Today is a restart once again.
今日もリスタート
The world is falling in love,
世界は恋に落ちている
an arrow of light piercing my heart.
光の矢胸を射す
I want to understand everything.
全部わかりたいんだよ
"Hey, tell me."
「ねえ、教えて」
Ignoring the blackboard, I steal a glance at
黒板 そっちのけで チラリ見詰める 先 は
甘い 横顔 ファンタジー
your sweet profile, a fantasy.
突然 校舎 の 裏 相談 恋愛 モード
Suddenly behind the school, a secret love mode.
やっぱり 私 に じゃ ない
Surely that's not for me, but
だけど あなた の 為 に 頑張る
I'll do my best for your sake.
いつ の 日 に か 振り返っ て みせる わ
Someday I'll make you look back at me.
鈍感 過ぎ て もどかしい ロメオ さん
You're way too dense, Romeo!
ハピハピ ハッピー クレセント
Happy, happy, happy crescent,
最高ですか？
Is it the best?
(最高です！)
(It's the best!)
幸せですか？
Are you happy?
(幸せです！)
(I'm happy!)
最高ですか？
Is it the best?
(最高です！)
(It's the best!)
幸せですか？
Are you happy?
(幸せです！)
(I'm happy!)
お付き合いしちゃって
We started going out,
同棲とか始めちゃって
even moving in together.
好き好き大好き困っちゃう
I like you so much it gets frustrating!
新郎新婦になりたーい！
I want to be a bride and groom!
ハイ！ ハイ！ ハイ！ ハイ！ ハイ！ ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
ぺこマリ
PekoMari!
ハイ！ ハイ！ ハイ！ ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
ぺこらとマリンはてぇてぇ！
Pekora and Marine, hey! hey!
婚約指輪はどうするの？
What about the engagement ring?
給料半年分くらい？
About half a year's salary?
新居の間取りはどうするの？
How about the new apartment's layout?
7LDDDKK！ (えっ！？)
7LDKKK! (Huh?!)
世界一可愛くなるから
Since I'll become the cutest in the world,
世界一かっこよくいてね？
you'll be the coolest in the world, right?
愛してるも毎日言って
Tell me you love me every single day,
あと「大好き」も忘れずに！
and don't forget "I love you" too!
お父さんお母さん
Mom and Dad,
お許しください 結婚します
please give us your blessing, we're getting married!
ご祝儀！ もっともっともっと積んでいいぺこー？
Congratulations! Pour even more, more, more blessings, Pekora?
お願いい
Please!
人生最高の日面に 祝福を受ける二人
Receiving blessings on the best day of our lives,
好き好き大好き困っちゃう
I love you so much it gets frustrating,
新郎新婦の入場！
The bride and groom enter!
大好きな人 大切な人
Someone I love so much, someone precious,
力合わせて生きていきます ちゅ！
we'll join forces and live on, smooch!
ハイ！ ハイ！ ハイ！ ハイ！ ハイ！ ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
ぺこマリ
PekoMari!
ハイ！ ハイ！ ハイ！ ハイ！ ハイ！ ハイ！
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
ぺこらとマリンはてぇてぇ
Pekora and Marine, hey! hey!
新婚旅行はどうしよう？
How should our honeymoon be?
沖縄で水着とか着たいな
I want to wear a swimsuit in Okinawa!
ホテルでは何を食べようか？
What should we eat at the hotel?
私の手作り料理 ♡ (なんで！？)
My handmade cooking ♡ (Really?! )
世界一可愛いお前と 将来添い遂げると誓う
I swear to walk by the side of the cutest person in the world forever.
愛してると言うよ
I'll say "I love you,"
Dear, pretty pretty my sweetest rabbit.
おじいちゃんおばあちゃん 娘もついに 結婚します
Uncle and aunt, your daughter is finally getting married!
子育ての秘訣？
The secret to raising kids?
そうねー 夫婦として当たり前のことを
Well, just taking what's natural for a married couple
当たり前にするだけなんだけれど 強いて言うなら 二人の愛
and making it natural, but if I dare say, our love!
人生最高の日面に 祝福を受ける二人
Receiving blessings on the best day of our lives,
好き好き大好き困っちゃう
I love you so much it gets frustrating,
新郎新婦の入場
The bride and groom enter!
大好きな人 大切な人
Someone I love so much, someone precious,
力合わせて生きていきます
we'll join forces and live on!
妄想乙！！
Imaginary delusions!!
人生最高の日面に (はぁ！？)
On the best day of our lives (Ha?!)
祝福を受ける二人 (もうええて)
receiving blessings (Come on now)
好き好き大好き困っちゃう (うん、困るなあ)
I love you so much it gets frustrating (Yeah, it's frustrating)
新郎新婦の入場 (はぁ 歌うかな)
The bride and groom enter (Hah, should I sing? )
大好きな人 大切な人
Someone I love so much, someone precious,
力合わせて生きていきます
we'll join forces and live on!
ぺこマリ最強！！
PekoMari is the strongest!!
最高ですか？ (最高です！)
Is it the best? (It's the best!)
幸せですか？ (幸せです！)
Are you happy? (I'm happy!)
最高ですか？ (最高です！)
Is it the best? (It's the best!)
幸せですか？ (幸せです！)
Are you happy? (I'm happy!)
花の塔
Tower of Flowers
作詞・作曲:さユり
Lyrics & Music: Sayuri
君が持ってきいちゃ漫画
The manga you brought home,
くれた知らない名前のお花
and the flower with an unknown name you gave me.
今日はまだ来ないかな?
Is today not coming yet?
初めての感情知ってしまった
I've come to know these brand-new feelings.
窓に飾った絵画をなぞって 一人で宇宙を旅して
Tracing the painting on the window, traveling the universe alone,
それだけでも不自由ないけど
even just that isn't free, but...
君の手を握ってしまったら
Once I held your hand,
孤独を知らないこの街には もう二度と帰ってくることはできないのだろう
I'm sure I can never return to this city that knows no loneliness.
君が手を差し伸べた 光で影が生まれる
You reached out your hand, shadows born from the light.
歌って聞かせて この話の続き
Sing and let me hear the rest of this story.
連れて行って 見たことない星まで
Take me away to a star we've never seen.
誰の手も声も届かない 高く聳え立った塔の上へ
To the top of a tall tower where no one's hands or voices can reach.
飛ばすフーセンカズラ
Fuzensankazura,
僕は君に笑って欲しいんだ
I just want you to smile.
君が持ってきた漫画
The manga you brought
くれた知らない名前のお花
The flower with an unknown name you gave me
今日はまだ来ないかな?
Will you not come today either?
初めての感情知ってしまった
I've come to know a brand new emotion
退屈な日々を蹴散らして
Scattering these boring days away,
君と二人でこの街中を泳げたら
if the two of us could swim through this town,
それはどれだけ素敵なことでしょう
how wonderful that would be?
出したことないほど大きな声で
With a louder voice than I've ever used before,
やっと君に伝わるあの秘密な光
at last my secret light reaches you,
岬とちょうどいいさ
right by the cape, it's just right.
世界の端と端を結んで
Connecting the edges of the world together
窓に飾った絵画をなぞって ひとり宇宙を旅して
Tracing the painting on the window, traveling the universe alone
それだけでも不自由ないけど
even that wouldn't feel inconvenient, but
僕は選んでみたいの 高鳴る心迷いだけの空を
I want to choose a sky of beating hearts and mere hesitation,
安全なループを今、書き換えて!
rewrite the safe loop right now!
君の手を握ってしまったら
If I were to hold your hand,
孤独を知らないこの街には
in this town that knows no loneliness,
もう二度と帰ってくることはできないのでしょう
we probably could never return again, right?
いくらでも迷いながら 光も影も見に行こう
Let's go see both light and shadow while getting lost however much we want.
歌って聞かせて この話の続き
Sing and let me hear the rest of this story,
連れて行って見たことない星まで
take me all the way to a star I've never seen before.
世界の端と端を結んで
Connecting the edges of the world together...
つっぱることが男の たった一つの勲章だって
Being defiant is a man's sole badge of honor,
この胸に信じて生きてきた
I've lived believing that in my heart.
泣きたくなるような辛い時もあるけど
Even when there are painful times that make you want to cry,
いつも俺たち がんばってきた
we've always done our best.
時の重さに流されそうになった時でも
Even when we felt like we were being swept away by the weight of time,
歯をくいしばり耐えてきた
we clenched our teeth and endured.
ガキのころ 路地裏で見た
When we were kids, in the back alleys,
夜空に煌めいていた
we saw the night sky sparkling,
流れる星を見て 誓った思いを
and watching the shooting stars, we swore an oath
忘れちゃいけないぜ
that we must never forget.
つっぱることが男の たった一つの勲章だって
Being defiant is a man's sole badge of honor,
この胸に信じて生きてきた
I've lived believing that in my heart.
氷のように冷たい 世間の壁が
The walls of society, cold as ice,
いつもさえぎる 俺達の前を
always block our path.
胸にえがいた この夢は 半端じゃないから
This dream we painted in our hearts is no half-hearted thing,
かじかむこの手 握りしめ
so gripping our numb hands tight,
ガキのころ 赤トンボ 追いかけてた時の
back when we were kids chasing red dragonflies,
燃えていた瞳は
the eyes that burned bright
つっぱることが男の
Standing tall is a man's...
たった一つの勲章だってこの胸に信じて生きてきた
...only badge of honor in this heart.
つっぱることが男の
Standing tall is a man's...
たった一つの勲章だってこの胸に信じて生きていく
...only badge of honor in this heart.
つっぱることが男の
Standing tall is a man's...
たった一つの勲章だってこの胸に信じて生きていく
...only badge of honor in this heart.
星座になれたら
If we could become a constellation...
もうすぐ時計は6時
It's almost six o'clock.
もうそこに一番星
The first star is already out there.
影を踏んで 夜に紛れたくなる帰り道
On my way back home, stepping on shadows.
どんなに探してみても
No matter how much I search,
一つしかない星
there's only one star.
何億光年 離れたところからあんなに輝く
Shining so brightly from millions of light-years away.
「いいな 君は みんなから愛されて」
"How nice, you're loved by everyone."
「いいや 僕は ずっと一人きりさ」
"Not really, I've always been all alone."
君と集まって星座になれたら
If we could become a constellation together,
星降る夜 一瞬の願い事
a fleeting wish on a star-filled night.
きらめいて ゆらめいて 震えてるシグナル
Sparkling, swaying, a trembling signal.
君と集まって星座になれたら 空見上げて 指をさされるような
If we could become a constellation together, pointing up at the sky,
つないだ線 解かないで
don't untie this connected line.
僕がどんなに眩しくても
No matter how dazzling I might be...
もうすぐ時計は8時
It's almost eight o'clock.
夜空に満天の星
The night sky is filled with stars.
何億光年 離れたところには もうないかもしれない
Maybe that star millions of light-years away has already faded.
月が綺麗で 泣きそうになるのは
The moon is so pretty it makes me want to cry,
いつの日にか 別れが来るから
because farewells always come one day.
君と集まって星座になれたら
If we could become a constellation together,
流星みたい 流れるひとりごと
a solitary murmur like a shooting star.
消えていく 残像は 真夜中のプリズム
The fading afterimage is a midnight prism.
君と集まって星座になれたら
If we could become a constellation together,
切なる願い 誰かに届いたら
if this earnest wish could reach someone,
変われるかな 夜の淵をなぞるような こんな僕でも
could I change the abyss of the night, even a nobody like me?
遥か彼方 僕らに出会ってしまった因果だから
Meeting each other far, far away must be destiny,
何度もしだってしまおうよ 雲の隙間で
so we'll meet again and again between the clouds.
君と集まって星座になれたら
If we could become a constellation together,
夜広げて 描こう絵空事
let's spread out the night and paint an imaginary sky,
暗闇を 照らすような 満月じゃなくても
even if it's not a full moon, to light up the darkness.
たくても だから
Even if... That's why
集まって 星座になりたい
I want us to gather and become a constellation.
色彩の光 放ような
Like emitting a myriad of colors of light,
つないだ線 解かないよ
I won't untie the line connecting us.
君がどんなに眩しくても
No matter how dazzling you are...
あの子が昨日 なんかすごく優しくて
That girl was acting strangely sweet yesterday,
(君じゃなきゃダメみたい)
(I think it's gotta be you)
こちらとしては そんなつもりないけど
It's not like I meant for it to go that way, but
(君じゃなきゃダメみたい)
(I think it's gotta be you)
いや バレてんじゃん ってか聞こえてんじゃん それ
No, you totally caught, wait, you heard me, didn't you?
(君じゃなきゃダメみたい)
(I think it's gotta be you)
頭の中 お花畑だとか少女漫画だとか もう なんだってどうだっていい
The inside of my head is like a field of flowers, or a shoujo manga, oh, whatever, none of that matters anymore.
そう 今すぐ君に会いたい
That's right, I want to see you right now,
君に会って確かめてみたい
I want to meet you and find out for sure.
世界のことわり 愛の定義 幸せのカテゴリー
The logic of the world, the definition of love, the category of happiness,
まだまだ君を知りたい
I want to know more and more about you.
こんなセリフ柄でもないけど
Lines like this aren't really my style, but
どんなに格好つけてたって始まりゃしない
No matter how cool I try to act, nothing's ever gonna start.
君じゃなきゃダメみたい
I think it's gotta be you.
今ごろになって気づいたところでさ
Now that I've finally realized it,
(君じゃなきゃ意味がない)
(It has to be you, or it means nothing)
明日も家の前通るわけだけれど
I'll still be walking past your house tomorrow, though
(君じゃなきゃ意味がない)
(It has to be you, or it means nothing)
いや 分かってんじゃん ってか期待してんじゃん それ
No, you totally knew, wait, you were expecting it, weren't you?
(君じゃなきゃ意味がない)
(It has to be you, or it means nothing)
この際 噂話だとかご近所付き合いだとか もう なりふり構ってられない
At a time like this, rumors or neighborly relations, I can't afford to worry about appearances anymore.
そう 確かに君しかいない
That's right, you're truly the only one,
君だけにはありのままでいたい
I want to be my true self only around you.
笑い転げたり 愚痴垂れたり 泣きべそ強がったり
Bursting into laughter, complaining, crying and trying to act tough,
この世でただ一人みたい
It feels like you're the only one in this world.
自分でも笑っちゃうんですけど
Even I find myself laughing at it, but
他の誰かじゃもう満たされやしない
No one else could ever satisfy me anymore.
君じゃなきゃ意味がない
It has to be you, or it means nothing.
今すぐ君に会いたい
I want to see you right now,
君に会って確かめてみたい
I want to meet you and find out for sure.
世界のことわり 愛の定義 幸せのカテゴリー
The logic of the world, the definition of love, the category of happiness,
まだまだ君を知りたい
I want to know more and more about you.
こんなセリフ柄でもないけど
Lines like this aren't really my style, but
どんなに格好つけてたって始まりゃしない
No matter how cool I try to act, nothing's ever gonna start.
君じゃなきゃダメみたい
I think it's gotta be you.
捕まえちゃう!
I'll catch you!
(どこにいるの? ムリよムリよ どこにいたってムリよ)
(Where are you? No way, no way, no matter where you are, it's impossible!)
捕まえちゃう！
Catch you!
どこにいるの？ ムリよムリよ どこにいたってムリよ
Where are you? No way, no way, no matter where you are!
捕まえちゃう！
Catch you!
だれといるの？ ダメよダメよ 私以外はダメよ
Who are you with? No way, no way, no one except me!
甘いよ甘い そんな装備じゃ
You're so naive, with equipment like that
逃げられるわけ無いじゃない
There's no way you can escape!
狙いをつけて 密かに背後から
Taking aim, stealthily from behind
I love you!
私のことを 好きになるはず
You're bound to fall in love with me
I love you!
そこに正義があるの
That's where justice lies
何度も言わせるつもりなの？ おや おや
How many times will you make me say it? Oh my, oh my
抵抗するならしてごらん！ 痛い 一歩
Try and resist if you can! Just one step
我が儘だって知ってるけれど
I know I'm being selfish, but
私の方が噂なようね
I seem to be the one everyone's talking about
冷たい言葉 優しい視線
Cold words, gentle gaze
獲物は…君だよ！
My prey is... you!
Cutie Panther 私 どこでも行くよ
Cutie Panther, I'll go anywhere
君の 君の 心盗んでみせるよ
I'll steal your, your heart away!
Cutie Panther 私 どこでも行くよ
Cutie Panther, I'll go anywhere
君の 君の 心を離さない
I'll never let go of your heart!
熱いよ熱い 愛のルールは 破られるため在るんだよ
Hot, hot are the rules of love, they exist to be broken!
ずるい笑いと意地悪な微笑みは
A cunning smile and a teasing grin
I miss you!
好きのせいだし悪くないでしょ
It's because I like you, so it's not my fault, right?
I miss you!
それが重度の恋よ
That's severe love!
絶対全ていただくよ？ おや おや
I'm going to take everything, you see? Oh my, oh my
抵抗するならしてごらん！ 手強いんだから
Try and resist if you can! Because you're tough
偽って歌う歌顔よりも 私のこと信じてみてよ
Instead of faking a song, try believing in me!
優しい言葉 冷たい視線
Gentle words, cold gaze
獲物は…君だよ！
My prey is... you!
Cutie Panther 君の瞳が欲しい
Cutie Panther, I want your eyes
私 きっと きっと盗んでみせるよ
I'm sure, I'm sure I'll steal them away!
Cutie Panther 君の瞳が欲しい
Cutie Panther, I want your eyes
私 きっと 素早く逃がさない
I'm sure, I'll never let you escape quickly!
何度も言わせるつもりなの？ おや おや
How many times will you make me say it? Oh my, oh my
抵抗するならしてごらん！ 痛い 一歩
Try and resist if you can! Just one step
我が儘だって知ってるけれど 私の方が噂なようね
I know I'm being selfish, but I seem to be the one everyone's talking about
冷たい言葉 優しい視線
Cold words, gentle gaze
獲物は…君だよ！
My prey is... you!
Cutie Panther 私 どこでも行くよ
Cutie Panther, I'll go anywhere
君の 君の 心盗んでみせるよ
I'll steal your, your heart away!
Cutie Panther 私 どこでも行くよ
Cutie Panther, I'll go anywhere
君の 君の 心を離さない
I'll never let go of your heart!
どこにいるの？ ムリよムリよ どこにいたってムリよ
Where are you? No way, no way, no matter where you are!
捕まえちゃう！ だれといるの？ ダメよダメよ 私以外はダメよ
Catch you! Who are you with? No way, no way, no one except me!
捕まえちゃう！ どこにいるの？ ムリよムリよ どこにいたってムリよ
Catch you! Where are you? No way, no way, no matter where you are!
捕まえちゃう！ だれといるの？ ダメよダメよ 私以外はダメよ
Catch you! Who are you with? No way, no way, no one except me!
明日、今日よりも好きになれる
I'll love you more tomorrow than today
溢れる想いが止まらない
These overflowing emotions won't stop
今もこんなに好きでいるのに
Right now I love you so much
言葉に出来ない
I can't even put it into words
君のくれた日々が積み重なり
The days you've given me accumulate
過ぎ去った日々 2人歩いた『軌跡』
The path we walked together through the passing days...
僕らの出逢いがもし偶然ならば?
Whether our meeting was coincidence?
運命ならば? 君に巡り会えた それって『奇跡』
Or fate? Just the fact that we met is a miracle
2人寄り添って歩いて
We walk close together,
永久の愛を形にして
making our eternal love tangible
いつまでも君の横で 笑っていたくて
I want to always be smiling by your side
アリガトウや Ah 愛してるじゃまだ
"Thank you" and, ah, "I love you" just aren't enough
足りないけどせめて言わせて「幸せです」と
But at least let me say, "I'm happy"
いつも君の右手の平を
Whenever your right palm
ただ僕の左手の平が
Is gently enveloped by my left palm
そっと包んでくそれだけで
Just feeling that love alone
ただ愛を感じていた
made me feel your love
日々の中で 小さな幸せ
We found little happinesses in our daily lives
見つけ重ね ゆっくり歩いた『軌跡』
And walked slowly along our path
僕らの出逢いは大きな世界で
Our meeting in this vast world
小さな出来事 巡り合えた それって『奇跡』
Was a small event; meeting you was a miracle
うまく行かない日だって
Even on days when nothing goes right
2人で居れば晴れだって!
Being together makes it clear skies!
強がりや寂しさも忘れるから
We can forget our bravado and loneliness
僕は君でなら 僕で居れるから!
Because with you, I can truly be myself!
だからいつも そばに居てよ『愛しい君へ』
So always stay by my side, "To my beloved"
2人フザけ合った帰り道
The way home where we joked around
それも大切な僕らの日々
Those are also our precious days
「想いよ届け!!」と伝えた時に
When I finally got the courage to say, "Reach my feelings!!"
初めて見せた表情の君
The expression you showed for the very first time
少し間が空いて 君がうなずいて
After a brief pause, you nodded in agreement
僕らの心満たされてく愛で
Our hearts overflowing with love
僕らまだ旅の途中で
We're still on our journey
またこれから先も何十年
And for decades to come from now on
続けていけるような未来へ
Towards a future that will keep going
例えばほら 明日を見失いそうに
For instance, even if we seem to lose sight of tomorrow
僕らなったとしても、
and become lost...
2人寄り添って歩いて
We walk close together,
永久の愛を形にして
making our eternal love tangible
いつまでも君の横で 笑っていたくて
I want to always be smiling by your side
アリガトウや Ah 愛してるじゃまだ
"Thank you" and, ah, "I love you" just aren't enough
足りないけどせめて言わせて「幸せです」と
But at least let me say, "I'm happy"
うまく行かない日だって 2人で居れば晴れだって!
Even on days when nothing goes right, being together makes it clear skies!
喜びや悲しみも全て分け合える
We can share all our joys and sorrows
君が居るから 生きていけるから!
Because you're here, because I can keep living!
だからいつも そばに居てよ 『愛しい君へ』
So always stay by my side, "To my beloved"
最後の一秒まで
Until the very last second
明日、今日よりも笑顔になれる
I'll smile more tomorrow than today
君がいるだけで そう思えるから
Just having you here makes me feel that way
何十年 何百年 何千年 時を超えよう
Across tens, hundreds, thousands of years of time
君を愛してる
I love you
ここで告知ですカーン！
And now, an announcement!
今年も出ます！うさだぺこら誕生日記念グッズ2024イェーイ！
This year's Usada Pekora Birthday Goods 2024 are out! Yay!
まずはラインナップはこちら！タラ〜ン！
First up is the lineup! Ta-da!
今回はライブのテーマでもある学校グッズ！
This time, it's school-themed goods matching the live's theme!
これを手に入れるだけでPEKO ACADEMY生になれる！
Just getting these will make you a PEKO ACADEMY student!
じゃあ1つずつ見ていこうぺこ！1つ目はこ・ち・ら！
Let's check them one by one, peko! First is right here!
皆様、いよいよ卒業するかい？
Everyone, are you finally graduating?
なんと入学1日で、U.P.アカデミーは卒業できちゃうぺこなんだ！
In just one day since enrollment, you can graduate from U.P. Academy, peko!
ま、グッズにめったの卒業証書とかって珍しくていいぺこだなとか思いつつも
Well, graduation certificates for merchandise are rare and nice, peko, while thinking that,
見て下さい！はぐれママが書いたぺこちゃん！
please take a look! Peko-chan drawn by Hagure-mama!
もう綺麗、かわいい、最高ぺこです！
She's so pretty, cute, and the best, peko!
しかもこの卒業証書は、棚とかにね、飾れるぺこなので是非とも飾って頂きたい！
Furthermore, you can display this graduation certificate on a shelf, peko, so please definitely display it!
そして2つ目は、こちら！
And the second one is, here!
ぺこらの学習帳！
Pekora's Study Notebook!
これでたくさん勉強や落書きをして欲しいぺこ！イラストは奥に先生です！
I want you to do lots of studying and doodling with this, peko! The illustration is by Okuni-sensei!
教師の裏にはなんとなんとなんとなんと！ぺこちゃんの新作ポエムがあるみたいぺこ！
And on the back of the cover, there seems to be a brand new poem by Peko-chan, peko!
このためにぺこら、何作品か提出させていただきました！
For this, Pekora submitted several works, peko!
是非ともお楽しみに！
Please look forward to it!
ま、このノートをね、学校でも会社でもお家でもたくさん使って欲しいぺこ！
Well, I want you to use this notebook a lot at school, at work, or at home, peko!
続いて3つ目は、こちら！
Next, the third one is, here!
かわいい！白ウサギの着ぐるみを着たぺこらのおでかけぬいぐるみキーホルダー！
Cute! Pekora's outing plush keychain wearing a white rabbit kigurumi!
ま、鞄とかにつけてね、たくさん色々なところに連れてって欲しいぺこ！
Attach it to your bag or somewhere, and take it to lots of different places, peko!
ぺこらはなかなかね、家から出ないので、是非ともこのぬいぐるみキーホルダーを連れてってぺこらが、ん、どっか旅行に行った感じの気分になるようにして欲しいぺこです！
Since Pekora rarely leaves the house, peko, please take this plush keychain along so that Pekora feels like she went on a trip somewhere, peko!
しかもこの表情も、たまらない！
Plus, this expression is irresistible!
そして4つ目は、こちら！
And the fourth one is, here!
U.P.アカデミーのトートバッグ！
U.P. Academy's tote bag!
さっきのね、おでかけぬいぐるみキーホルダーをつけたら、もう完璧！
If you attach the outing plush keychain from earlier, it's already perfect!
このトートバッグはシンプルな形なので、めちゃめちゃ使いやすいぺこ！
This tote bag has a simple shape, so it's super easy to use, peko!
そして、そしてよ、U.P.アカデミーのこのロゴ、見てよ！めちゃめちゃおしゃれだし、もう学生気分も味わえじゃん！
And, and you know, look at this U.P. Academy logo! It's super stylish, and you can really get that student vibe, peko!
ま、いろ々なね、用途で使えると思うぺこなので、たくさん使ってくれると嬉しいぺこです！
Well, I think it can be used for various purposes, peko, so I'd be happy if you use it a lot, peko!
そしてこちら、フルセットを購入してくれた方には、箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入りのポストカードがついてくるぺこ！
And here, those who purchase the full set will get a postcard with a foil-stamped duplicate signature & message, peko!
表情もね、にっこりとしてかわいいぺこちゃんなので、
The expression is also smiling and cute Peko-chan,
あとはあともメッセージもなんて書かれてくるかお楽しみに！
so look forward to what kind of message will be written as well, peko!
フルセット以外にも単品でも買えるので、気に入ってくれた方はぜひとも手に取ってもらえると嬉しいぺこ！
You can also buy items individually besides the full set, so I'd be happy if those who like them can pick them up!
販売時間はこのライブが終わった10時からぺこです！ぜひともよらぺこ！
Sales time starts at 10 o'clock after this live ends, peko! Be sure to check it out, peko!
U.P.アカデミーへのね、入学お待ちしてます！
We look forward to your enrollment in U.P. Academy!
そしてそして、この後10時15分からは、メンバー限定のアンコールライブがはいぺこ！
And then, from 10:15 onwards, there's a member-limited encore live, peko!
何の曲を歌うのかな？踊るのかな？
What song will she sing? Will she dance?
メンバーの方はそちらもお楽しみに！
Members, please look forward to that as well!
それでは、ぺこらありがとうライブはここまで！見てくれた人本当にありがとう！これからもよらぺこ！
Well then, Pekora Thank You Live ends here! Thank you so much to everyone who watched! Keep supporting me from now on, peko!
また次の配信でお会いしましょう！バイバイン！
Let's meet again on the next stream! Bye-bye!